welcome back to am Northwest from an
invitation to Studio 54 to a bow tie worn
by Mick Jagger here with a groovy pop
art collection we welcome back antique
appraiser Gary Gman great to see you
again thanks for having me back okay you
have some really interesting things here
really interesting this all came from a
collection or that a fellow who was that
I'm working for was an executive in the
record business back in the day in New
York okay and uh he's retired and and
he's downsizing as everyone does and so
can we sell and they got these things
it's really cool and um I'll show you
this let's start with the shirt and the
tie these are from a company called Mr
Fish and this was a brand new thing to me
Mr Fish of London made all the Psychedelic
and cool clothes for all the rock
stars back in the 60s think Austin Powers
look oh yeah yeah with all the crazy
psychedelics this this shirt silk shirt
was allegedly I haven't had it DNA
tested but allegedly worn by mck Jagger
as well as the I totally see Mick
Jagger wearing this shirt yeah and it
it's all silk and and but if you're if the
people out there are looking through
their closet or their friend's closet says
Mr Fish snag it that's a $400 shirt if
we can prove it was MC Jaggers it goes up
from there but I don't think I ever will
yeah but that's incredible fun but Mr
Fish Mr Fish and this is an
amazing find too this is fun he
was he was a hipster this man okay
back in this is an invitation to um
Studio 54 Studio 54 all happen you
used to hang out with Liz Anda there
didn't you back in the day back in the
day exactly um Anda and Liz all good
friends hang out and Jackie O and all
they uh uh this was you had to get this
invitation for
1983 wow here let me shake it and it'll
be great for people to see there we go
but 1983 uh New Year's Eve
party and this is blows
up and as balloon I'm not going to this
heart and it was an invitation to a
Valentine's Day event at Studio 54
become very collectible CU it's so iconic
and it was only there for like three
years you think they were there forever um
it was only there for three years like
three and a three three and a half years
A lot happened in those three and a half
years A lot happened okay seems like
yesterday seems yes an invitation to
uh W invitation to uh yeah wedding uh
Whitney Houston and Bobby Brown's wedding
this is an invitation that he had and
it looks kind I mean it just looks like
any almost any other yeah and then it
had in here in Le of gifts to give
to the Whitney Houston foundation for
children that's great and so but how but
what would something like this get you
then it's Whitney Houston is another
one that people she's just iconic that
everybody wants uh I think I'm still
researching between $500 and $1,000
somebody would pay for that have a piece
of their their history of that history
yeah that's crazy okay these boxes he
just found now they're they're interesting
boxes I mean and there they're made but
you has a little plaque on the inside
here and on the inside of the flat one
that the Timbers for these boxes were
made from the HMS Victory which
was um Admiral Nelson's Flagship
back in the 1700s okay so when they
Salvage it they made it but what makes it
even more interesting yeah is the gifts
that were in them were wedding gifts to
Prince Charles and Lady Diana no and
they took the gifts and threw the boxes
away and so the butler going through the
dumpster out behind Kensington Palace
um and got a letter from his Charles's
Butler explaining that these were
boxes that were gifts had gifts in
them for Princess Diana and Charles
incredible and um you know I haven't
researched a value I I don't know if I can
find a comparable on it uh Prince course
anything it's like um Whitney Houston
anything Princess Diana is a big such
a big big deal is that because she's
passed on Yeah well yeah she died and
both of them died young and uh were such
at the peak of their popularity and it
just kind of we have an affection for
them yeah these are amazing and so just
the idea that I mean it's historic and
that it's such a famous ship and you
know especially in England more than here
but such a famous ship that the the
Timbers came from how would you prove that
that's where those the wood came from
there well they have a little plaque on
them so okay just like me I can tell if
it's Sterling because it says Sterling
on the bottom there you go that's how you
tell I'm a professional I can tell how
you tell Goa all right let's talk about
this right here this is kind of my
childhood sort of a thing I'm bringing
up you know Lord of the Rings is such a
huge deal but before the current Lord of
the Rings there was another Lord of the
Rings and it was illustrated by the
brothers uh uh hilderbrandt were these
German artists that did this and this
is what the The Fellowship of the Ring
looked like and they Illustrated the
books and they Illustrated a Hobbit movie
back in the day oh that didn't do really
well because they didn't they had too
much stuff this is actually
this is actually a calendar from
1976 and so you got the road
here yeah so anybody who's a
tolken fan and under the age of 50 have
no idea what this is they're over the
age of 50 they may remember these this
is tree beard and all the different
characters and it and it's it's the the
and and so it's a fun thing and it kind
of I I was a geek in high school who just
loved the trilogy of the Rings and and
so this really hit hit home to me personally
I don't get too excited personally
about things you know like that but it
triggered great memories for me and um
love it and it's not worth they're about
anywhere from $25 $35 to buy one for
the artwork and stuff but they're
but it's it's that kind of emotional
connection I got you it's it's it's a
Memory I love that oh wow and back in
the 60s
um conspiracy theories are big today
well there was a big conspirac after keny
died and still kind of going who killed
Kennedy we want to believe somebody else
and this is a cograph done by guy named
William Kent and he did a whole series
of stuff protest stuff and again it kind
of brings back my when I was a kid all
this stuff was going on I I was I didn't
know you know what do I know um when
when you're a kid but uh now I kind of
remember that it was during the protest
eras any of that sort of stuff political
stuff from that period has gotten to be
really hot especially related to the
kennedies yeah and that that looks so
familiar seeing that out yeah aming
yeah so it's about $1,000 PL now
thank you so much that's fun I just
thought this was so much fun I've been
getting a kick out of all of it this
week yeah you I guess you got to pay
attention to estate sales from people
who worked in the music business yeah
right I have a friend they when he
goes to EST estate sales he'll say who
something about the person they were
there and if they have you know their
career was something he was interested
and he'll be first line that's perfect
awesome thank you so much Gary great
to see you again great finds all right
we'll be right back with more
am Northwest stick around
[Music]